So you're someone that's got a really
small one, like a YouTube channel.
You've got a small YouTube channel,
and you're wondering: How do I make money?
Well,
I've got a pretty good way to explain this
to you.
As many of you are aware,
I've got a Porsche 911 GT3, and I love it.
It's branding my bill.
It's a bloody manual.
But everyone I know
that owns one seem to do the same thing to
theirs.
They change the exhaust.
So I put in a message to one of my
friends.
I said, "Look,
if I want to do an exhaust in a Porsche,
who do I call?" And he
said, "There's a guy called Raz.
He's got a business called Prestige Auto
Works.
They're based in Melbourne,
and they're based in Sydney.
Give him a call." So I did, and it
was one of the most expensive things I've
ever
done in my life, and I'll explain why.
So the exhaust comes in two parts.
These bits are called headers,
and the air goes through that,
through these things,
which are called catalytic converters.
Now, excuse my Ugg slippers,
this bit here takes out all the gnarly
stuff,
but it also makes it sound a little bit
quieter.
Then this catalytic converter connects to
a muffler.
Now, if you get a cat-back system,
you keep this bit in place, and
that bit just
shoots out. Now,
I'll take you behind my fridge to where I
store
el muffler. Now, this bit here
is to make sure that the sound isn't too
loud to-- Basically,
this bit takes all the fun out and,
[muffler sound] yeah,
there's valves in that,
but there's valves in the new one.
So I said, "Raz, get this off.
Get them stinking headers off and give me
a proper exhaust."
And here's a bit of footage from the time
that we had it done.
And you'll notice that my car
is white because I get it wrapped a lot.
Now, when I was chatting to Raz, he goes,
"Look, we can do stainless steel, or we
can do titanium." I go,
"What's the difference?" And he goes,
"Look, mate, to be
perfectly honest,
you don't want to find yourself at a
traffic light next to
another GT3. You rev it, you've got steel.
They rev it,
they've got titanium." I said,
"Titanium me up." I said, "Get me them
carbon fiber tips as well. Okay,
how much is this going to cost?" 27 grand.
Yeah, $27,000. Give or take £13,000.
It's quite a lot, but here's my defense.
Yeah, this car is built for handling.
It's built for the track,
but I'm on the track 1% of the time with
it.
And although it handles really well
and it's got that amazing grip,
day to day, I'm
not really getting to know the grip
because in the wet, it's a death trap,
and in
the dry,
I'm mostly just taking it to the
supermarket to get some bananas for
my son or some nappies.
The time I really have fun in it is
when I floor it and the
exhaust kicks in and makes a bit of noise.
The time it really puts a smile on my face
is when I go through tunnels and I
clutch in second gear. Ba!
The enjoyability I'm getting
from it is more in the noise than the
G-forces in the corners.
Therefore, the exhaust had to go. I said,
"Raz, transferring you the money." Now, I
made a grave error, and
that grave error is sat right behind me.
If I asked you with these titanium headers
to spot where the
catalytic converter is in it,
you wouldn't be able to because there
is none.
Now,
there's two things you should know about
catless headers.
One, they're illegal as shit, and two,
it's loud.
It was straight piped, and
if I drove it for too long, my ears would
ache to the point that I was worried I
was going to go deaf.
And don't worry, YouTubers,
we're getting to the point of this video
very, very
soon.
So I had to put my tail between my legs,
call Raz again, and go, "Love the
setup. Love the titanium tips.
Love the IP exhaust.
I love everything about it.
But I'm going to need a new set of headers
with
200-cell cats in because these catalytic
converters, zero fun.
These catalytic converters,
it sounds like a Formula 1 car has fucked
a
fighter jet."
[car revving] My God.
[car revving] And I'm worried. I'm even
worried what my neighbor's thinking.
I'm worried about what people three
postcodes away are thinking
when I've just cold
started the car at 7:00 in the morning.
So I call up Raz.
I say, "Look,
I need the other headers." Another 15K.
So yeah, what we're looking at here
is about £6,000 worth of
titanium that's just sat in my gym as an
ornament.
So if any of you do have a 992 GT3,
at this point,
you can just have them because
there sits a reminder how much of a
fucking idiot I am.
However, I will be honest with you,
there are some days
that I do miss the fucking
straight pipe catless going,
"Wah." I do miss the earache
and the earbleeds that I
have at the end, and some days, I think,
"Do you know what?
I'm going to put a ramp in here,
and just occasionally,
I'm going to jack the car
up, I'm going to take the headers out,
and I'm going to go catless, maybe on the
weekends." And when you hear a fucking
typhoon fighter jet going past, it's just
me with my earplugs in. All right,
let's get to the point.
I said to Raz, "Mate,
why aren't you posting on YouTube?"
And he has started
posting on YouTube now since.
And I just put it down to real simple
economics. I said, "Raz, there
is going to be a certain
amount of views before someone buys."
There
is going to be a CAOVBSB,
certain amount of views before someone
buys.
And I said for him,
that could be as little as 500 views.
Because think about it,
500 people watch a video about a car with
an
exhaust being fit. Chances
are maybe only 10% of them
are going to be in
Australia between Sydney and Melbourne.
So already 400 wiped out.
But out of those 100 people that
geographically live close to it,
they're wanting something from that video,
and the
thing they're going to want
is something transformative.
So here's another really important thing
for people to realize.
When people watch your videos about a
transformative process, whether it's an
exhaust, getting wrapped, losing fat,
they are thinking about themselves in that
period.
When they're seeing me enjoy the car with
the exhaust, ba, down the street,
they're really thinking of themselves
doing it to their car.
So then I said to him, "Look,
if 500 views get you a customer," or
even I could say to him, "Bro,
out of 500 views, how many of that
equates to a sales call like the one you
gave me?" And let's be honest, once he was
on the phone with me,
even though I'm not the biggest fan of
sales calls, the way
he said,
"You're at a red light parked up against
another car," straight away, I
thought, "Do you know what?
He's right." So the lesson to take from
this is
whatever niche you're in, there
is a certain amount of views you need for
someone
to buy your product. Now,
depending on the product, the offering,
what it is, you
could just be selling someone a call,
a consultation, but you need something to
sell. Now,
the beautiful reason as to you being,
let's say, a smaller channel is
you've not made the mistake
that a lot of YouTubers make.
They think if they want to make money,
they need to have loads and loads and
loads of people watching their videos to
make money from AdSense, and that's just a
terrible idea. Now,
any money you get from Google, cool,
but it should be just a
bit of fun money.
Every YouTube channel should sell
something.
I actually had someone join my mentorship
this week, and he kicked off a bit
because he sent me this long spiel about
how he wanted to be helped in business and
all this. I go, "What
is it you're selling?" He goes,
"You haven't answered my
question." I go, "What
is it you're selling?
Because I don't know what it
is you're selling, and that's a problem.
If I,
the person you've just paid thousands of
dollars to help you with your
business,
don't have a fucking clue what you sell,
your prospects haven't got a
fucking clue." So as a small channel,
everything should be geared around selling
One unit. And ultimately,
you don't need thousands of views to get
sales calls,
or thousands of views to sell loads
and loads and loads of your product.
There's a certain amount of views before
someone buys your stuff, or inquires, or
downloads your lead magnet.
And then from there on in,
it's just really a numbers
game. So for Raz, let's go his YouTube,
500 views equals one
call.
We could then say three calls equals two
sales.
Now suddenly, that 500 views
is equal two sales, which could equate to
$30,000 of sales.
Let's say he's running at a 10% profit
margin, he's
now making 6K from 500 views. Now this
is basic maths, of course,
but the point I want to make clear is
if he wanted to make 6K from views,
he would
need hundreds of thousands,
sometimes even millions,
depending on the CPM.
Which is,
depending on the type of content you're
making, your CPM would differ.
And every business should really have this
all thought out.
Then ultimately, this maths here
is going to change video to video.
So you boxed it off, you go, "Cool,
this was one type of video." Then you
might go
away and make another video,
and it's 1,000 views per call.
Then you might do a deep dive video on the
intricacies of a fucking exhaust setup,
on why to go cat-back versus full kit,
whatever.
It might even be 300 views per call.
Now, metrics like this, my sensei,
Ed Lawrence,
has got a platform called RevTrack,
and that means that I can actually see
which videos perform the best.
I can track how many sales
were made direct,
and also I can just see how
many clicks were occurring.
Let me take you upstairs and show you.
I am also hosting a free three-day event
where I teach all of this about making
content, getting leads, making money.
You can register to that for free.
There's a link in the description.
There's also going to be a link in the
comments.
So I know it's kind of messy,
but here there's the dashboard from
everything I've
been pushing,
because everything's going to the
three-day webinar.
I can actually see here the amount of
clicks each video is getting that I've put
out recently.
I can also look at the revenue,
and I can also show you that some of
my videos have done $49,000, 23,000,
20,000,
et cetera. Because this
is my small YouTube channel.
My big channel, sure,
it does like a couple K a month in views
or whatever.
But smaller channels, your side channel
or your small YouTube project, should be
all about getting people on your landing
page to buying your product, or booking in
calls, or inquiring or whatever it is.
Because it takes so much more pressure off
you.
Raz, when he gets to make car content,
and the meta for him is that he can enjoy
it. And because he does this day in,
day out with car exhausts, he has
everything he needs coming into his
workshop where he can just pick up a mic
and
go, "Hey, this is what we're doing today,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
If you're interested in doing a custom
exhaust, inquire in this form below." Then
the thought that he can get two bookings
from a few thousand views is liberating,
and it should be the same for you.
Because even this video right now,
and even if I
go through this channel,
which some people think is like, "Oh,
his fallen
off channel," which is fine,
they can think that.
My most recent video, 9.2K, 2.9, 10K, 9K,
5K, 3K, 4K, 3K. Well, that one did 51K.
All right, it's actually doing all right.
But the video that I showed you before
that had done
$49,000,
don't even think hit 10,000 views.
Point of this video
is to detach your beliefs
that views equal money, and that
AdSense is how you make money as a
YouTuber.
Your job on YouTube is to make videos.
And again,
I've got a silver play button course
that will help you.
I put that together for YouTubers.
It's a couple of hundred bucks.
There's a link to
that in the description as well.
But the idea is that there's only a
certain amount of views you need for
someone to
do the outcome that you want,
whether it's click on your lead magnet,
buy from you,
book in a call, work with you one-to-one.
And that's really all you need to do.
In the onset when I started my mentorship,
I just opened one-hour calls with
people, and I charged 500 US dollars,
which isn't a huge deal.
And by the interactions I
was having with people,
it helped me build out the rest
of the mentorship as to how it looks
today.
So the crazy thing here
is YouTube to the outsider is about
getting the most amount of views possible,
but it's not.
It's about getting the most amount of
inquiries or sales from a single video.
Once you can switch to that mindset
and detach yourself from views equal
money, you
can make more money.
So please make sure
that you've registered to that webinar.
There's going to be a link in the
description and to the comment below.
If you're someone
that hasn't started your YouTube channel
yet, I've made this
video which explains exactly why it
is so important that you get started.
If you're not even a small channel yet,
you must watch this. Bye-bye.